[birds chirping]
[♪ Forever Loving You ♪
by Nora Aunor playing]
♪ Why did I ever say goodbye? ♪
♪ Why did I ever make you cry? ♪
♪ When all the while
I knew you cared ♪
♪ And love's just starting
To be real ♪
♪ I blame myself for losing you ♪
♪ I was a fool to let you go ♪
♪ My restless night has found me so ♪
♪ Come back once more, I beg of you ♪
♪ Regrets fill my heart,
Now I need you ♪
♪ I'm longing to start life anew ♪
♪ Forgive and forget,
Now I'm learning ♪
♪ And I'll try
Not to hurt you again ♪
♪ And after all the things
I've done ♪
♪ I've known that there is only one ♪
♪ My roving days and nights
Are through ♪
♪ I'll stay forevеr loving you ♪
WHAT'S MINE IS YOURS
WHAT'S THE TEA?
WITH OGIE DIAZ
What a shocker!
What is this, huh?
- [camera shutter clicks]
- [crowd cheering]
[thrilling music]
They say it's a star-studded list.
Of course,
it's a red-carpet premiere.
First on this list
of confirmed attendees
is this power couple
which we'll refer to
as "The Lady and the Champ."
Ooh...
You can't miss this!
Look out for these stars
who are said to arrive too.
Super and Duper.
Ooh!
Slay! [gasps]
But wait, there's more!
This kid is definitely showing up.
The Comeback Kid.
And this is indeed a comeback!
A star-studded reunion like this
is a rare event, I tell you!
It's crazy,
it's like a meteor shower!
So stay tuned, my tea-loving friends.
Because whenever
there's a meteor shower
you can expect a big bang!
[laughs]
[coughs]
WHAT'S THE TEA?
WITH OGIE DIAZ
[theme music]
♪ Careful, careful ♪
♪ The world is full
Of jealous people ♪
♪ When envy strikes,
It means trouble♪
♪ That's why we need to be careful ♪
♪ Careful, careful ♪
♪ We always need to be careful ♪
♪ Prying eyes ready to snoop ♪
♪ Digging for the juiciest scoop ♪
♪ That's why we need to be careful ♪
♪ Careful, careful ♪
This looks good.
Um, can you deliver
to the office by 6 p.m.?
Yes, ma'am,
we'll make this a rush order.
- [Andrea] Thank you.
- My condolences.
Thanks.
I'll take these too.
- [Andrea] Can you deliver this now?
- [vendor] Sure, ma'am!
- Those are freshly made.
- [Andrea] Thanks.
[dramatic music]
[Samuel in English]
We've come far, Matthew.
[in Filipino] SAM would not be SAM
if I didn't convince you to join me.
I want you to know that
it's you that I trust the most.
Don't make any decisions
until I get back.
[dramatic music continues]
[dramatic music fades]
[Gina in English]
Matthew, your coffee's ready.
Shoot, I'm late.
[in Filipino]
I'm sure they'll understand
why you're late.
[in English] Especially Samuel.
But it's so tragic.
[in Filipino] I didn't know
Samuel was buried in debt!
But still, that's not a good reason
to kill himself.
[in English]
He died of a heart attack.
[in Filipino]
I already told you, Gina.
But I saw it right here!
Oh!
It's a blind item!
[Matthew] This was written by idiots.
I'll tell you if he killed himself.
[in English] I'm not so sure.
[in Filipino] I know you.
You have a lot of secrets.
[Gina chuckles]
Wait.
Did you ever tell Samuel
about Paul Amir's offer?
No.
Nobody knows.
[in English]
Actually, it's just an offer.
Nothing's final.
[in Filipino]
I guess it's for the best.
It would have hurt Samuel.
Maybe you don't have to leave SAM.
What do you mean?
[in English] Well, Samuel is gone.
And SAM cannot continue
without a leader.
[Gina in Filipino]
Which one of you will take his place?
[in English]
And who deserves it the most?
[Samuel in Filipino]
I've tried everything.
I put up a business,
I went into sales.
But I was never really into it.
I became a producer too,
but it was too difficult.
And I never really made it
as an actor.
But when I became a manager
I was happy.
It was something else, believe me.
[exclaims]
Hey, that's not allowed here.
[clatters]
Take all of these upstairs.
Careful.
[thrilling music]
[Camille] Yes, sir.
Yes, you may leave the flowers
at the reception area.
Yes, you can come visit any time.
[thrilling music continues]
- Good morning, Dad.
- [Matthew] Good morning.
Morning, Dad.
Camille?
Sir?
Do you need me to call Camille?
[exhales sharply]
What's going on downstairs?
Memorial service.
[Matthew] Here?
It's Mother Aleta's idea.
It's for industry colleagues.
[Gab] Sofie's making the calls
to them.
[Andrea] It's okay.
At least it's private.
If anywhere else
and our talents show up
so will their fans.
It will be chaotic.
It's embarrassing
and Samuel's wife wouldn't like it.
Helen is coming here?
[Andrea] I don't know.
How will we get any work done today?
What's your problem?
Mother Aleta's taking care of it.
Look.
We haven't really
talked about it, but...
what will we do
about Samuel's talents?
[Matthew] How do we split them up?
Wow.
I seriously don't know.
[in English] I just think that
we should come out with a statement.
A "moving forward" statement.
You know what, Matt?
[in Filipino] Samuel's body
hasn't even arrived from Germany
and we're already
splitting his talents?
[in English] Don't you think we have
to find a perfect time for this
- and not tonight?
- [Matthew in Filipino] Then when?
What if Samuel's talents leave us?
Why would they do that?
[in English] Come on, Gabriel.
You think they're here because of us?
The only reason they're here
is because being managed
by Samuel Mendiola is a big deal.
The ultimate star-maker.
Look, now that he's gone...
You know, I...
I love Samuel
just as much as the two of you.
But knowing him,
I mean, he would want to see
that SAM is running smoothly
even without him.
For example...
[in Filipino] You think he'd be happy
you passed up on Kiray's big break?
[scoffs]
[in English]
I told you, I'm handling it.
[scoffs] How?
[Andrea] Can you just
leave him alone?
Matty.
[in Filipino] I don't have
to update you about my talents.
Then who will you update?
- There's only three of us left.
- [Gab sighs]
[Matthew]
We three will have to run SAM now.
How do we do that? No meetings?
No more brainstorming?
Andrea, how?
[knocking on door]
[Camille] Excuse me.
Not now, Noemi.
Ms. Andrea,
Ms. Maricel is in your office.
There. There's your update.
Maricel Soriano is in my office.
Happy?
[Andrea in English] Let's go.
[door closes]
[gasps]
[in Filipino] This is it?
This is the great new project
you have for me?
[scoffs]
SORIO AND TEKLA, UNDERAGE,
TARAY AND TEROY
QUIAPO KID, TAKEN FROM HEAVEN,
SUPER NANNY AND THE GOLDEN DUCK
YOUR HAND, PLEASE, TOMORROW IS MINE,
PEPE AND PILAR
This is the best Shine can do for me?
- [Camille] Hi.
- [mumbles]
[in English]
What are you talking about?
[in Filipino]
A lot of people would kill
just to play Paula on this project!
And the role is yours!
[in English]
I know and the role fits me well!
- Right?
- [Andrea] Exactly.
[in Filipino]
Now, if we had Jodi Sta. Maria
or Eula Valdez in it with me
I may reconsider.
But Snooky? Oh, my god!
She will be the death of that film.
You're still mad at Snooky?
After all this time?
It's forever.
The nerve of that woman!
The audacity. How dare she!
Why don't I just...
Why don't I do
that other project instead?
- Juan Makabayan?
- Yes.
Oh, there's nothing in there for you.
I read the script.
Of course,
I looked for a perfect role for you.
Something that stands out,
but there's nothing.
Maybe I should just let my aunt
manage my career.
The accountant or the nurse?
The dentist.
Sure, she knows nothing
about managing
but at least she cares about me.
I only signed with you
because of Samuel.
Because he promised me
he'd take care of me.
That he'd give me
everything I wanted.
And most of all,
he promised that Snooky and I
would never, ever be
in the same film again.
This is all Samuel's fault!
He decided to become
a stupid drug addict at his old age.
I mean, what 70-year-old dies
of a drug overdose?
Hey.
Samuel never did drugs.
He died of a heart attack.
Oh, did he, really?
[scoffs]
Well, whatever.
He's dead, so there's no one
who cares about me anymore.
[Maricel] Maybe I should
switch agencies.
Galaxy's there.
Or Aunt Metring might do better.
Ms. Mary,
you don't have to decide now.
We can talk some more
when you come back for the memorial.
What makes you think I'm attending?
I'm so disrespected here.
Too bad you're not coming
since Director Mac will be there.
[Andrea] He wants to see you
and Snooky.
Just a preliminary meeting...
Snooky's coming?
Yes, that's what Gab told me.
She has a lot of ideas
and suggestions for the film
like what to add in her scenes
in the film.
- Oh, darn fairy!
- Where's the fairy?
- There.
- Oh, yeah, that's a fairy.
Found it.
- Chin?
- [Chin] Oh, I didn't notice you.
I was looking for my contact lens.
Oh, hello, Ms. Mary!
How'd they end up on the floor?
They fell out, I don't know.
- I'll message you, okay, Mary?
- [Maricel] Yeah.
[Chin] Camille, I need your help.
Come with me.
Girl, that is so old news.
You really should know these things.
You're in showbiz now, so keep up!
Were we already alive then?
Yes, we were in diapers, probably.
But anyway,
I'm sure you must have seen
their old movie on TV.
It's called What's Mine is Yours.
There were rumors that Maricel
was way better in it than Snooky.
[Chin] So Maricel
expected all the awards.
But Snooky won them all
like a grand slam.
Oh, my god.
And Maricel got nothing,
besides certificates of nomination.
For real?
Oh, my god, wait! There's more!
Did you know?
Maricel also told the press
that Sir Samuel and Snooky
were having an affair!
- That's absolutely correct!
- [gasps]
[Daisy] And get this.
Of course,
Snooky wouldn't stand for it.
She told the press that it was really
Maricel having an affair with him!
Oh, I heard that!
I'm confused. So which one was it?
Girl.
Both of them. Among others.
Sir Samuel was such a playboy!
[cackles] And...
Even Mother Aleta was one.
- Yeah!
- It's all crazy!
- Oh, and by the way...
- [Camille] Wait...
Who was he with
on that "orghi" in Germany?
What "orghi"? It's "orjee".
[Daisy] It's "orjee"?
They changed it?
No, it's always been "orjee".
[gasps]
How many people should there be
in an orgy, anyway?
What orgy are you talking about?
I'm talking about the orgy
that killed Sir Sam!
He couldn't handle
all the orgy action
because he was too old.
No, you idiot!
Sir Samuel died of a heart attack!
No, really?
Yes, that's what the doctor said.
- Oops! Wrong info.
- Goodness, Miss Daisy!
- I'm so sorry, friends.
- Now she's spread it.
- Fake news...
- Take that back!
- It's fake!
- It wasn't an orghi.
- There she goes again.
- Crazy.
But anyway, that's why we're here,
doing interior decorating
and writing thank-you cards
and thank-you letters
all for Mother's love
for Sir Samuel...
- Volleyball.
- What?
Volleyball!
[shrieks] Mother!
- Good afternoon, ma'am.
- Good afternoon.
You look very familiar.
But I'm pretty sure I don't know you.
Mother, this is Camille,
Ms. Andrea's new RM.
Ooh...
What's your last name?
It's Vergara, ma'am.
[somber music]
[clears throat]
We need some candles here.
- [Chin] Okay, right away, Mother!
- [Camille] Chin, candles.
[Chin] Check the RM's area.
I'll ask Sofie.
[softly] Uh...
Till we meet again, love.
Excuse me, Sir Matthew.
- Hey.
- Come here.
[Camille] Did I do anything wrong?
Yes.
You're here.
But I work here.
That's it.
There are many jobs out there.
I like it here.
I'm not doing this to you on purpose.
I know it's difficult.
But I've already
learned so much here.
And I don't know how to explain it.
I'm so tired.
I'm hardly getting any sleep.
But I am so happy.
I feel so alive.
Even if Ms. Andrea yells at me,
I don't mind.
Because I want to be as good as her.
As good as you.
Nobody knows about you.
And they don't have to know.
I call you Sir Matthew, don't I?
I know showbiz is a small industry.
[in English] We'll have to bump
into each other sometimes.
[in Filipino] I'm fine with it.
[dramatic music]
Camille, let's be clear, people talk.
They can't see us together
or they will find out.
You're smiling
'cause you found the candles, girl?
[gasps] Hi, Sir Matthew!
[indistinct chatter]
So how old is your godson?
Six, I think. I don't know.
This is only my second gift to him.
The first one was
for their Christening.
Oh, Sofie, girl
- you should be ashamed!
- [Sofie chuckles]
[tense music]
Sir Gab!
[Sofie] What are you doing here,
Sir Gab?
Uh... Checking these, why?
You're supposed to see Joey, right?
Oh, right!
[Chin] Mm...
[Gab] Shoot, here I go again.
- I'll be back soon.
- Wait, Sir Gab.
You can give this to him
to make up for being late again.
- You sure?
- Yes.
Thank you.
No gift for your poor godson, then.
It's okay, there's always next time.
[tense music continues]
[indistinct shouting]
[woman] Bye-bye!
Oh, you missed the party!
Hi.
Uh... Where's Joey?
He's at the bookstore with the nanny.
He got bored waiting.
[Lora] I stayed behind
to wait for you.
[exclaims]
I'm sorry about your boss.
[Lora] Poor guy,
he drowned alone in Germany.
- [bubbles burbling]
- [rubber duck squeaks]
Huh? He didn't drown.
Uh... It was a heart attack.
Can you text the nanny
and tell them to come back?
I can't stay long because
I have to go back to the office
for Samuel's memorial service.
- Please.
- You'll make him come back here
just to say goodbye?
And you want to ask for extra days
when you can't even do one day?
If you add up all the hours you've
spent with Joey since this started
it comes down to only three hours.
[scoffs]
Mm... Here's a souvenir.
You can get back to the office now.
[dramatic music]
[Kiray] Hi, Sofie!
Hey, Kiray, how are you?
[gasps]
I know.
It's so sad to hear about Sir Samuel.
Do you know what happened?
Mm-hm. It was cholesterol.
He died of a heart attack.
Huh?
Why did my mom say it was murder?
Huh? No, he wasn't murdered.
Where's your mom anyway?
It's just me today.
Is Uncle Gab here?
He stepped out, but he'll be back.
I'll just wait. Thank you.
- Okay, I'll send it right away.
- [Sofie] Yes, hello?
- Thank you.
- Yes.
- Okay.
- Okay, sir.
Oh, okay...
Kiray!
Uncle Matthew!
[Kiray] I'm here for Uncle Gab,
but he's out.
- I'm sure he'll be back soon.
- [chuckles]
You can wait for him upstairs.
It's a mess down here.
- Come on.
- Okay, thank you!
Your mom's not with you?
Uh... Actually,
I ditched her, Uncle Matt.
She thinks I'm at the gym.
Why'd you do that?
Because she keeps bugging me!
She's all, "Why not accept
the Hollywood offer?"
"It's Hollywood!"
So I need to talk to Uncle Gab
about my boobs.
Are they really that small?
[playful music]
Um...
[window blinds rattle]
What do you want for your career?
I have to ask Mama.
I'm asking you.
I'm really enjoying acting.
Even when I was a kid...
[Kiray] I loved playing
different characters.
I love comedic roles
and when I have to play the mean girl
or fight someone in a scene
no one gets mad at me
because they know I'm just acting.
I've been working since I was a kid.
The things normal kids do
like playing outside
and going to school...
I've never experienced any of that.
But I enjoy what I have.
I'm still enjoying myself.
Well, in this industry...
you have to be versatile.
If you want to get good roles
you have to be famous.
That's all your mom wants for you.
And I think that's what you need.
[Matthew] For instance,
that Hollywood project.
How many actors your age can say
they've starred in a Hollywood film?
But there's a price to pay for that.
Just like everything else.
At least, for you, it's only surgery.
- [Noemi] Ouch!
- [Sofie] Help me please!
Oh, come on! It's just flowers!
- Sir Matthew will look for me.
- No, but...
- [Noemi] He needs me there.
- [Sofie] I need you more, Noemi!
- You can do it. You're a big girl.
- Please!
[Noemi] Camille! Are you busy?
Not so much.
Take this upstairs and read the card.
I'll take care of this.
- Thank you, bye.
- Go, girl.
[Noemi] I don't want to be involved
in that.
Yeah, I'm telling you,
if you join Shine
your career will be revitalized.
My god, you aren't even here yet
and we already have plans for you!
What more when you finally move here?
[Andrea] Actually,
there's a perfect role for you
in Juan Makabayan!
Enough of those rom-com movies.
They're old news! They're so passé!
Okay, let's set a meeting, like,
around next week? Will that be okay?
Perfect, I'll let my RM Camille
message you or text you
to set the meeting.
Okay. No...
I don't need a charcuterie board.
We'll just make sure we give them
a proper notice, okay?
[in English] Bye, Bea! See you!
[in Filipino] What's this doing here?
I said to deliver this to Cassie.
Why is it here?
[sighs] You can...
Place these
with the rest of the flowers.
Go!
- Take care!
- [Kiray] Okay, thank you!
Bye, Kiray!
[Gab] Kiray!
- Hi!
- [Kiray] Hey, Uncle Gab!
Sorry, I went out
to see my son, Joey.
- What's up? Let's go to my office.
- [gasps]
No need, Uncle Gab!
I just ditched Mom,
sorry I couldn't wait for you.
I already spoke with Uncle Matthew.
I'll decide about Hollywood soon.
- Bye, Uncle Gab!
- [Gab] But we've decided...
[Matthew] Um...
[in English] By today.
I'm sure.
- No, that won't be a problem.
- Matty.
- Uh, I need...
- Can I call you back?
I'll call you back, bye.
Yeah?
[in Filipino]
What did you tell Kiray?
Nothing, I just brought her upstairs
to wait for you.
- Ms. Andrea, you need to come down.
- That's all?
Uh... Yeah.
No! And also, I congratulated her
on her big Hollywood break.
In the event that she decides
to get the surgery.
Chin is working extra hard,
searching for projects for Kiray.
In exchange for Hollywood.
We talked about this
in the meeting, right?
[breathing heavily]
Now what are you doing?
Why are you meddling with my talents?
Meddling? This is all for SAM.
Your talents are mine too.
That's nonsense and you know it.
Why bother splitting up our talents?
You mean to say, I get a cut
from your talents' earnings?
- Hey!
- Tell me it isn't crazy!
- Wait, no!
- Gabriel, listen to me, okay?
- What's happening here?
- Whatever happens to your talents
affects all of SAM.
I had to step in!
So how did it become nonsense?
- Wait!
- You didn't need to step in...
- Calm down!
- ...because I told you
- I was already handling it, Matty!
- It's for SAM!
- No, but you're not listening!
- Why're you not listening?
Helen!
Hi!
[tense music]
Um...
[in English] Helen, on behalf of...
of Andrea and Gabriel
and the rest
of Shine Artist Management
please accept my deepest
and sincerest condolences.
We're very sorry, Helen.
Your loss is ours too, Helen.
Samuel was like a father to me.
Actually, to all of us.
Yeah. He wasn't like a husband to me.
[stutters] You came in very early.
[Andrea in Filipino]
We weren't expecting you until later.
[Helen] I just wanted to find out
who organized this memorial service.
Uh...
Well, we didn't want
to bother your family.
Uh, so this is for friends
and colleagues in the industry.
Yeah.
[Matthew] Um...
Actually, it was...
Mother Aleta.
[scoffs]
- [Helen] I'm sure.
- And...
Well, speaking of Shine...
Uh... [hesitates]
Anytime you want to...
- Go on a tour.
- A tour!
A tour of the office.
I don't think you've ever been here.
And, also, at the same time
you can use Samuel's office.
Or any office, for that matter.
I mean, it's totally up to you.
And we'll just take it from there.
Then we can discuss how to split...
I mean, the...
How we should distribute
Samuel's talents
all of Samuel's talents
among ourselves.
Uh... [hesitates]
I think what Matthew's
trying to say is
right now, you have
so much to deal with.
You have to be with your family.
And these are the things
we can discuss in the future.
So you don't have to think
about that...
What the boys are trying
to say is that, you know...
[Andrea] You don't have
to decide tonight.
We can just set a meeting
some other time.
When you're ready,
we can talk about it.
And we're just here.
No, it's okay.
It's good you brought it up.
Actually, I was wondering
who would ask that first.
And, Matthew, you're right.
I've meant to visit many times
to find out exactly what it was
that was taking Samuel
away from me and my children.
[Helen] What is it with this place
that he comes home late every night?
If he ever does.
Why do I see more of him
in magazines and newspapers?
Why do I wake up
alone and without him by my side?
[in English] Well, you know...
Samuel worked really hard for Shine.
This is like his baby.
I wanted to be part of this.
[in Filipino] But he wouldn't let me.
Maybe he didn't want me
to know what he does here...
[in English]
Who he shares his bed with.
I just did everything I was told.
I brought my children up so well.
And I was a good wife.
That's why he spoke fondly of you.
[Helen scoffs]
No, he didn't.
[exhales sharply]
[in Filipino]
I don't need a tour or a meeting.
Don't you know
that Samuel left no will?
[in English]
Shine belongs to me and my children.
So as of tonight
Shine Artist Management
is for sale
to the highest bidder.
[staff 1] Guys...
- [crowd screaming]
- [staff 2] Guys, please, quiet!
Quiet, please! Guys, listen, quiet!
This is not a movie premiere
or a fan meet.
This is a wake.
A memorial service.
So please, there will be no screaming
or we will call the cops
to disperse you all.
- Do you understand?
- [crowd] Yes, sir.
- Okay.
- Be very quiet.
- Thank you.
[crowd screaming]
[thrilling music]
- [camera shutter clicking]
- [indistinct shouting]
Hello!
More pictures?
How are you?
- You're late again.
- So what?
You're such a joke.
Look at this.
[inaudible dialogue]
[Camille] Hello, good evening.
Sir Matthew is over here.
Oh, it's Laurice.
Sir Matthew.
- Matthew.
- Laurice!
- It's nice to see you.
- Nice to see you.
Mr. E, Mr. C, Laurice.
Yeah, and, of course...
Yes?
- Excuse me.
- Okay.
Camille, just a minute.
Malou, I hope you don't mind.
Camille, this is Malou Crisologo.
Line producer for Juan Makabayan.
And these two fine gentlemen here
are the producers
of that monumental film.
- This is Mr. E and Mr. C.
- Nice to meet you. Hello.
Malou, this is Camille.
- She's Andrea's new RM.
- Okay.
Okay, she just finished film school.
And she's so used to being on set.
Perfect. Perfect timing!
Because I am doing five movies
all at the same time.
It's giving me a headache.
Mr. E here is all paid up.
But we still don't have a location!
Sorry about that, Mr. E.
We've been to Spain so many times.
But we won't go over budget.
Uh... [nervous chuckle]
How about TV? Do you also do TV work?
Because I also have...
- I'm not really looking...
- No, of course she does!
- Not just TV and movies.
- Good!
And even commercials.
- Good.
- Not to worry.
- I'll send you her contact details.
- Yes.
- Yes, I'm on Facebook. ASAP, please.
- Thank you, Lou!
- Mr. E, Mr. C.
- [Sofie] My name is Sofie Lasola.
If you're looking for a new actress,
you can watch my play.
Okay, Sofie, thank you.
- Ma'am Aleta.
- Mm?
Um...
Now I want you to meet
two stalwarts of the industry.
This beautiful lady is none other
than Ms. Roselle Monteverde
- from Regal Films.
- I'm Camille.
- This is Camille.
- Hello, ma'am.
And this good-looking
gentleman right here
is none other than
- Mr. Vincent del Rosario...
- Hello.
...of Viva Films.
- Hello, sir.
- You've got in one room
Regal Films and Viva Films.
You can choose to be
a Regal Baby or a Viva Hot Babe.
- [all laugh]
- Matthew.
Hello, hi, nice to see you.
- Mr. Vincent.
- Hello, how are you?
Uh...
- [Gab] Mother.
- Gabriel.
Excuse me.
Here. Thanks anyway.
Why didn't you give it to Joey?
Uh...
He already had one.
Oh...
This is my gift to you.
Thank you.
[ominous music]
My condolences, Matthew.
[cell phone beeps]
[indistinct chatter]
[ominous music continues]
Excuse me.
- Hi.
Helen, I'm Paul Amir.
[Paul] And I'm really,
really sorry...
[indistinct chatter]
I hope there will be an opportunity
for us to talk sometime.
- Maybe over a cup of coffee?
- Excuse me. Helen?
- Paul.
- Yes?
I'll be back, okay?
[ominous music intensifies]
[both gasp]
[in English] I'm so sorry.
- It's okay!
- I'm so sorry.
Did I hurt you?
- No, it's okay.
- I'm sorry I ruined your flowers.
It's okay. I'm fine, no worries.
Um...
I'm Rina, by the way,
if you need anything.
Okay. I'll take note of that. Andrea.
[in Filipino]
What are you doing here?
[in English]
Paying my respects, of course.
[in Filipino]
It's a good turnout, right?
[in English]
Well, Samuel was very well-loved.
Oh, yes. I just met his wife, Helen.
[in Filipino]
I heard she's selling something.
Am I right, Matthew?
[in English] I'm sorry again, ma'am.
It's okay.
Uh...
Matthew.
[in Filipino] That's not yet final.
Really?
But Helen sounded so sure.
You still don't believe me, do you?
That, without Samuel,
Shine is going nowhere but down.
Paul.
If you think that Shine is worthless
why are you buying it?
And if Samuel is the only reason
for its success
why are you offering me a job?
- [in English] Sorry, again.
- It's okay.
[Paul in Filipino]
Because you're good at your job.
For all you know,
you might be the next Samuel.
It doesn't matter who buys Shine.
After all, I think that will help
with the transition.
They'll only buy it for the name,
then afterwards, close it down.
I'm still thinking about it.
[in English] I'm not sure
I can do that to Andrea and Gabriel.
Matthew.
[in Filipino] You may shine...
but we are the galaxy.
Do you want to be with them
so far down the ladder of success?
- [Noemi] Sir Matthew...
- [Daisy] Idol! Picture, please!
[Noemi] Sir Matthew?
- [Daisy] Thank you.
- [Noemi] Where's Sir Matthew?
Over here, guys.
Sir Matthew.
Matt!
- [Matthew] I'll call you.
- [Noemi] Sir Matthew.
Brandon and Jessica are here.
- [Matthew] Jess!
- [Jessica] Hey, Matthew.
- How are you? Good to see you.
- [Matthew] So nice to see you, hi!
- Brandon, buddy!
- How are you?
[Brandon] Good to see you!
[rock music]
[Brandon laughs]
- Good to see you!
- [Matthew] Yeah.
Good to see you too.
[in English]
I'd like you to meet some people.
- Yes, sir. Yeah.
- [Matthew] Okay.
This is one of our country's most
talented singers and actresses
Ms. Zsa Zsa Padilla.
- Nice to meet you.
- [Brandon] Zsa Zsa, how are you?
[Matthew] And her equally
talented daughter, Karylle.
Hi, Karylle. Nice to meet you!
And Samuel's widow, Helen.
Condolences, Mrs. Mendiola.
[Brandon] Ma'am, the world lost
a good man in Samuel.
I promise he's going to be missed.
That's for sure.
We also heard about what happened.
For us, we wanna make sure
that'll never happen to you.
We want to make sure that you could
always protect yourself.
So we got you this.
I know how classy you are,
Mrs. Mendiola.
So we got this for you,
just from Texas.
[in Filipino] It's beautiful!
- [in English] It looks nice!
- And deadly!
[nervous chuckle]
Brandon, I need a minute.
Okay.
- [Matthew] Excuse us.
- Excuse me.
[Helen] Will someone
please take this off me?
[Niño] Hi, ma'am!
Your ex and I had a movie together.
[chuckles] Mr. Director!
[romantic music]
[in English] Ma'am, your drink.
But I didn't ask for a drink.
I just wanted to say
you have beautiful eyes.
Uh...
By the way,
this is my personal number.
Please call me directly
if you need anything.
Yeah, sure, I'll...
Thank you.
Thank you. Have a good night.
Bye.
Maricel, Snooky, just in time.
[in Filipino] This way.
[thrilling music]
Let's get on with the meeting.
Wait a second.
[whimsical music]
Okay.
[Gab] Chin, look for Director Mac.
- Oh!
- [Andrea] Hi! Hello!
Um...
Hello.
[in English] Ms. Helen
I would like you
to meet our biggest stars
Ms. Maricel Soriano
and Ms. Snooky Serna.
Of course, I know them very well.
[in Filipino] Who doesn't know
these huge movie stars?
[Helen] And I know
Samuel worked on both of you
at the same time.
I mean...
on both of your careers, of course.
Actually, we're meeting
for a new project.
[in English]
So if you don't mind, excuse us.
- Let's go? Let's go.
- Let's go.
Did you get the bag that I sent you?
[in Filipino] Yes, Ms. Jessica.
I got it. Thank you.
[Noemi] Come in.
[in English] I heard a rumor
about Samuel.
[in Filipino] That he got shot.
[Matthew] Fake news.
He was on a date with Madel
when he had a heart attack.
I'll be outside.
And thanks again, Ms. Jessica!
[door closes]
[Matthew in English]
Hey, we're not doing that!
Noemi.
Yes, sir?
[in Filipino] Can you hand me
their advertising contracts
for Thorade and Manila Mansion,
please?
[in English] Right away, sir.
[door closes]
[door opens]
[Matthew] Thank you!
[door closes]
[Jessica] Get off of me, okay?
Do you want me
to divorce you right now?
[Brandon in Filipino] Try it!
Let's see if you can
afford this lifestyle.
Do you have a prenup?
Where is it?
Whip it out!
No prenup, no discussions, okay?
[in Filipino] I never wished
for anything bad on anyone.
You know that.
I'm not a bad person.
But my reputation was ruined.
Is it my fault that my performance
had the greater impact?
That I am the better actor?
I'm the one who was wronged.
I'm the one who was maligned.
I am the victim.
- Idiot.
- What the heck?
[Andrea chuckles]
What?
Oh, dear. She called me an idiot.
Did you hear that, Gabriel?
See how this woman treats me?
Oh...
Why would I want to work
with someone like that?
And what makes you think
I want to be anywhere with you?
If there was one movie left
in the universe
I wouldn't do it
if you're in it with me, humph!
You're so scared people will see
that I have more awards!
[Snooky] You're not
that good of an actor anyway.
- You're just jealous!
- Oh, no.
You want everything that I have!
[Maricel] Title roles, houses,
everything!
- Even Samuel! Right?
- [gasps]
I'm sorry to break your hearts
but there will be no divorce.
Thorade ends 2027.
Three commercials per year.
Manila Mansion, 2030.
- [Brandon] Oh, no.
- Four commercials per year.
[Matthew] It's stipulated
in both contracts
that you cannot divorce.
Divorce means breach of contract.
We know that.
We've been playing house long enough.
We can wait.
Well there you go!
[in English]
But after these two contracts
we don't want any more
couple endorsements.
[Jessica] We just want solo contracts
from now on.
Please, please...
So I don't have to look at this thing
even at work.
[Matthew] Okay,
this is the bottom line.
No one can know
that you want a divorce
and no one can definitely know
why you even want one.
Wait a minute.
Why do you want a divorce, anyway?
Well? Tell him why.
You have a personal "trainer," right?
- [Brandon] In that gym?
- [mouths] Shut up.
I wonder what you're training for.
He's your boyfriend, isn't he?
Ha?
Am I right?
[in English]
I'm a woman and I have needs.
I understand that during fight camps,
we can't do it.
But what about outside
of fight camps?
I still don't get any!
I'm just being careful!
[in Filipino] What if I go weak?
I don't want to get sick!
Samuel loved me first, Mary!
- Don't you call me Mary!
- There you go.
Not now, not ever!
You would visit Samuel
every single day!
Just because you know he liked me!
[Maricel] That's what it was!
[Snooky] You have it all wrong!
He was visiting me every day
because he was in love with me!
[Maricel] No, you're wrong!
- You went to him every day!
- [Snooky] No...
Okay, ladies.
We don't care how big Sam's penis is.
We have to talk about the project!
We're going off-track here.
- We sure are!
- Are we really going off-track?
- Yes, we are way off-track!
- Yes.
You have to do this film!
- I agree!
- You two are the reigning
Queens of Philippine Cinema!
[Matthew in English] Okay, guys.
This is what's going to happen.
Jessica and your fitness instructor
are no more.
You're never gonna
see each other again.
[in Filipino]
You have to step out of this room
looking like you are still in love.
You will always hold hands.
[in English] Come on!
Come on, Brandon, come on!
[in Filipino]
You will always be kissing.
Come on.
[groans]
And of course,
you will be all over each other.
[grunts]
Even before you step out,
they should start feeling it already.
[in English]
Come on, give me a smile!
Come on!
Come on, Brandon!
No, you give me your smile.
You give me your smile!
Get out of here! Come on!
You lovely couple, you.
Come on, there you go.
Imagine, two of the greatest actors
of this generation
in one historic film,
just imagine it!
[Andrea] Streaming services
will be fighting over this.
A Snooky Serna-Maricel Soriano movie.
Maricel Soriano as Paula
and Snooky Serna as Candida.
Perfection!
- And...
- Perfection!
- Wait.
- [Andrea] What?
Uh...
It's Snooky as Paula.
- No.
- [Gab] Maricel as Candida.
Yes.
- [Andrea] Gab, we agreed on this.
- Right, yes!
I said Maricel is perfect for Paula
and you agreed with me.
No, I agreed they were perfect for it
but it has always been
Snooky as Paula!
- Gab, you got it wrong again.
- No, I'm Paula!
I thought you knew how to compromise!
This is probably why Cassie left you!
Hey, Gabriel Anthony Soler!
- You want to make this personal?
- But I really didn't...
Your wife left you because
you always go back on your word!
- I'm just trying to prove a point!
- I said Maricel is Paula!
- That's not what we talked about!
- She's the only one for it.
- We agreed Snooky is Paula!
- You agreed with me. No!
[clamoring]
Ms. Andrea!
Director Mac is here!
[Andrea] Who was first, huh?
Between us?
Please move, everyone!
Hold on, Sir Matthew.
- They're in an acting workshop.
- A workshop...
What kind?
- [chuckles]
- Stanislavsky? Adler?
- [Helen] Until the very end...
- Morris?
Shine has done nothing
but embarrass me.
Bye, Matthew.
Don't be fooled
by a smooth-sailing production.
If a film gets made with no problems,
it will flop.
But if it's problematic and messy
then that's a sure box-office hit!
[in English] What a day, huh?
[in Filipino]
I know you didn't like it
when I introduced you to producers.
[in English]
I just wanted to give you options.
[in Filipino] I'm good here.
You're here.
[in English] You know, Camille...
I grew up here.
[Matthew] Samuel was my mentor.
And now he's gone.
[in Filipino] But there's a lot more
for me out there.
And I'm not sure if SAM can keep up.
You have so many secrets, huh?
I'm sure you have your reasons
but if I don't know
what you're going through
or why you're keeping
those secrets...
I really can't help you.
I just want you to know
that I didn't want
to mess up your life.
You said we can't be seen together.
I said, that's fine.
But Ms. Andrea hired me.
I figured maybe the universe
did it for me.
If we can't be father and daughter
we can still be together somehow.
My dream somehow came true.
Come on.
- I'll drive you home.
- Okay.
Let's go.
[somber music]
[Matthew] Gab.
What's your problem?
You're my problem.
[in English] Stay away from Kiray,
let me handle it.
[in Filipino]
I'm just trying to help.
Don't worry, Gab.
Matthew won't bother you anymore.
He won't meddle with Kiray because
he's too busy sucking up to Helen.
I'm not talking to you either.
[sarcastic chuckle]
Oh, wow. You're mad at me?
- Who brought up Cassie?
- Excuse me.
Not another scene.
I've had it with both of you.
Hello, Laurice. Sorry, I know.
- [Andrea] Hi. Let's go in?
- I know.
[Madel crying] Why, Samuel, why?
[wailing]
Why?
Samuel...
[sobbing]
Who is this?
It's Madel.
[Aleta] She's tried so many times,
but she still hasn't reached the urn.
Just because
she was with him in Germany
doesn't mean she can act like this.
Why can't she be as quiet
as Samuel's other mistresses here?
Which ones are they?
You see that woman over there,
with the veil?
- That's Rowena.
- [Andrea] Mm-hm.
That one, near the urn?
Mm?
- [Aleta] That's Grace.
- [Andrea] Mm-hm.
This one behind me on the left.
- Don't look. I said, don't look.
- Mm-hm.
That one is Chiqui.
Further back, two rows away,
is Sabel.
- The other one over there is Bambi.
- Mm-hm.
Who else?
See that one?
The one with the flower on her head.
- [Aleta] See her?
- [Andrea] Yeah.
That's Cynthia.
And... [clears throat]
You okay?
Of course.
I've been okay for a while now.
[sighs]
[Aleta] Wait.
Mm?
What happened
between you three earlier?
[exasperated sigh]
[in English] It's a hopeless project.
[in Filipino]
Everyone wants the Paula role.
Maricel and Snooky hate each other.
So, it's a no-go.
[in English]
It's really... It's hopeless.
It's not gonna happen.
Andrea!
[in Filipino]
What do you mean it's hopeless?
Don't ever think it's hopeless.
Let me handle Maricel and Snooky.
What you need to fix
is all this fighting
amongst you managers.
You can't carry on that way.
You have to end it soon.
Samuel will roll in his grave,
I tell you.
Okay, I'm going to take a walk.
I've seen this movie already.
[somber music]
[indistinct dialogue]
[somber music continues]
[thunder rumbles]
[Matthew] Take care.
[rain pattering]
They say rain means blessings.
You know what, Matthew, you're right.
We need to have a plan for SAM.
Okay. Let's figure it out.
So, with your permission
I'll let the other RMs know.
They can get everything ready
for this planning session.
Of course.
Hi, Uncle Gab.
Kiray?
[Gab] I can call Kelly.
She said we could
change our minds, so...
I'm sure she'll be glad
you're taking it.
I just hope
she forgives me for yelling at her.
And I'm sorry.
Why are you apologizing, Uncle Gab?
I feel that I didn't protect you.
I was no help to you at all.
I'm good!
This will be helpful to me.
Oh, think of it this way.
This will boost my confidence
and inspire me to work harder.
Listen to me.
Your career
isn't the only important thing.
You're still young.
[in English]
You should be enjoying yourself.
[in Filipino]
I am enjoying myself, Uncle Gab.
[Kiray] I really want to do this.
Because of this,
I can make more films.
I really love this.
Thank you!
[laughs]
Thanks, God!
[Mrs. Celis] This rain won't let up.
Mommy?
[in English] Freebie.
Wow, Gab.
We're going to Holy Wood!
Yeah, Hollywood!
Holy Wood!
- Holy Wood!
- Yes, Hollywood!
[whimsical music]
Mm!
Michael, this is too salty.
Add some water.
Will do.
Are they here?
- [cook] Order, Table 6.
- [server] Copy.
[Aleta] It's Maria. Mm!
Hello!
[over speaker] Still no Cookie?
How can anyone be late
for a Zoom call?
[gasps]
[notification beeps]
Mother, where is Maria?
[Snooky] I thought we had a meeting.
Mother, you know I hate waiting.
God, these two. Hold it up higher!
[assistant] Yes, Mother.
[notification beeps]
Still not here?
Am I supposed to wait for her?
Are you sure we need Mary here
in the meeting?
Mother personally invited me, hello.
You know, you two...
In America,
they call this an intervention.
[Aleta] But here in the Philippines,
we call it
"I'll knock you both senseless
if you don't fix this mess."
- [gasps]
- [flame roars]
What was that, Michael?
Okay.
Let me ask you this.
Who produced Underage and Schoolgirls
and all the films
that made you famous?
- You did.
[Aleta] Mm! Hey, Michael.
The squash is excellent!
- Make this again!
- [Michael] Yes, ma'am.
Who paid for your debts
when you squandered your earnings
from those movies?
- You did.
And who do you thank for everything?
- First, God.
- I want to thank you.
- [Snooky] My family. And...
- [Maricel] The production.
- And... Samuel, Andrea.
- Samuel, Gab.
- And then, of course, Shine.
- My mom and dad.
- Okay, I get it.
- [Snooky] Right, Mother?
We'll do it this way.
The Portrait of An Artist
as a Filipino.
You're both doing it.
[Aleta] Maricel, how old are you?
Fifty-four.
How about you, Snooky?
Fifty-three.
Maria, you'll play Paula.
Snooky, you are Candida.
Period.
Think of your fans, okay?
When we're all dead and gone
they will remember you,
they will never forget you
because of this film.
So do it.
Yes, ma'am.
[ringing]
Hey, Rey! How's my piano?
[piano key plays]
Nice!
[Mac] I'm really excited.
Everything's set.
Just the small matter of billing.
Yes, and I go first, right?
Here we go again.
[Snooky] Oh?
I'm an award-winning actress.
All my films make money.
[Maricel] So if I get top billing
this movie will make money.
If not, that won't happen.
Are we doing this for the critics?
If they're the only ones
who'll watch, then why do it at all?
Maricel.
[Snooky] You got the part you wanted
so I should get
the billing I deserve!
Director, hold this for me please.
Okay.
- How are we...
- I've had it. I've really had it.
- [Snooky] Now she's upset?
- Pass this to Sir Gab.
She stole my role,
now she wants to steal my billing.
[Maricel] Because that's the only way
to get people to watch this movie.
- Pass this to Sir Gab.
- She wants to get her way
- even though it's clear...
- From Camille.
...that I deserve top billing.
- [Maricel] Oh, don't kid yourself.
- Sir Gab.
We all know who the true star is.
[Snooky] And we all know
who the better actress is.
Delusional is what you are.
[Maricel] And you?
You're out of your mind!
[Snooky] Let's see your awards then!
Actually, I think Camille
has a solution here.
Can you explain?
Uh...
The graphics will be a circle
turning constantly like this.
Your names will be in the circle
so no one is on top or the bottom.
Then we can create separate
social media pages.
And separate posters.
[Noemi] One for Paula
and one for Candida.
[film rolling]
Fantastic! Yes!
[Mac in English] I love it! Love it.
Love it. It's nice, right, Maricel?
Back to you.
And back to you.
[Mac] We need to do
an ocular ASAP, okay?
- The interiors are very important.
- [Aleta] It went very well.
- [Aleta] Thank you!
- [Mac] Thank you!
- Bye!
- Take care!
Oh, I love you. It's so cute!
- [overlapping dialogue]
- [dog barking]
[exhales sharply] Congratulations!
- Your kids are very smart!
- Of course!
Everyone in SAM is smart!
Agree. Okay, I'm going!
- Thank you so much, Mother!
- Bye, Mother!
Thank you.
- Bye!
- [Gab] Take care!
- [Andrea] Bye, Mother!
- [Aleta] Bye-bye!
- Bye, Mother.
- Bye-bye!
- See you!
- [Maricel] Thank you.
Something's wrong with this one.
Oh...
Is this my dog?
I should go.
- Bye-bye!
- Bye!
[relieved sigh]
- So?
- [Andrea] I think we have a project!
Good job.
[Gab] I didn't think it was possible,
but they finally agreed on something.
- [Sofie] Ms. Andrea.
- [Andrea] What?
What is it?
[Andrea] Oh, no.
[shudders]
- [moaning]
- [notifications pinging]
My god.
Noemi.
- No...
- My god.
[closing theme music]